Guide to the Arthur H. Landis Papers ALBA.066
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Arthur H. Landis Papers
1915-1944; 1965-1985
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Landis, Arthur H., 1917-1986
ALBA.066
4.5 Linear Feet (5 boxes)
Arthur H. Landis (1917-1986) was a U.S. volunteer in the Spanish Civil War. Arriving in Spain in April 1937, he first served as a scout, a typographer, and an artillery spotter with the (Canadian) MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, and later served with the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. In 1967, Landis wrote The Abraham Lincoln Brigade about U.S. volunteers in the Spanish Civil War, and later published Spain! The Unfinished Revolution, about the political complexities of the war. The Arthur H. Landis Papers contain correspondence and writings produced between 1960 and 1985; family papers, 1910-1940, and miscellaneous ephemera and artifacts relating to Landis's service in Spain.
Provenance
The Arthur H. Landis Collection was donated to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives by Arthur H. Landis in the early 1980s. This collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Historical/Biographical Note
Arthur H. Landis (1917-1986) was born into a family of vaudeville performers in Birmingham, Alabama in 1917, and spent most of his youth in Redondo Beach, California. During the Depression, Art Landis moved across the Western states picking up work in canneries and mills, and on fruit farms. In April 1937, at 19, he went to Spain to fight in the Spanish Civil War. He served as a scout, typographer, artillery spotter, and commissar with the (Canadian) MacKenzie-Papineau Battalion, and fought in the battles of Aragon and Teruel, where he was injured. Landis also worked for a stint for an intelligence unit, and participated in an abortive operation to blow up the Italian Fleet headquarters. Just before Barcelona fell to Franco's forces, Landis helped load the 15th International Brigade archives onto a Soviet ship. He sailed back to the U.S. on the R.M.S. Ausonia in December 1938.
Shortly after his return to the U.S., Landis married Ruth Jurow and went to work for her father as a ladies clothing salesman in Rochester, Minnesota. Struggling financially, Landis and Jurow moved to Mexico City before settling in California in 1944. Landis and Jurow later divorced. It was in the mid-1950s that Landis began to pursue a career as a writer. In 1967 he published The Abraham Lincoln Brigade, an account of the experiences of Americans who fought in the Spanish Civil War. The book was based largely upon the reminiscences of Lincoln Brigade veterans, which Landis collected via correspondence and on audiotapes (the latter comprise the bulk of the Arthur H. Landis Oral Hustory Collection [ALBA Audo 66]). The year his book came out, Landis was awarded a medal by the Presidium of the Soviet Committee of War-Veterans for his "great contribution in the history of the struggle of the Internationalists against fascism on the battlefields of Spain." In 1972, Landis published Spain! The Unfinished Revolution, about the political complexities on the Republican side of the Spanish Civil War. The book was published by Camelot Publishing, a company run by Landis with close friend and fellow SCW veteran, Manny Harriman. Despite a bitter dispute with the leadership of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) in the mid-1970s over the unauthorized translation into Russian of one of his essays, Landis remained devoted to VALB throughout his life, contributing occasional articles to the association's newsletter, The Volunteer, and maintaining close associations with many VALB members.
In addition to his political writing and radical activism (he participated in the anti-Vietnam War movement in the 1960s, among other activities), Landis established himself as a fantasy and science fiction writer. He published, edited and wrote for Coven 13, a fantasy magazine, in the late 1960s, and wrote a series of fantasy/science fiction novels (occasionally under the pen name "James R. Keaveny," after an old family friend). Landis also published and wrote for Dealer's Voice, a motorcycle magazine. Through the 1970s, Landis worked occasionally as an automotive parts firm's truck driver to supplement his writing income.
Landis died of bone cancer in January 1986 in Los Angeles.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of correspondence and writings of Arthur Landis, family papers, and miscellnaeous items of ephemera and artifacts, some realting to Landis's service in the Spanish Civil War.
Series I: Family Files, consists of correspondence (including local postcards) of Arthur Landis's mother, Alice Fries with friends and family as she traveled to small towns across the Midwest and West working variety shows as a singer and dancer. Fries became Alice Landis when she married William N. Landis, Arthur's father. William, also a performer, entered the army in 1920. By 1922 the couple was estranged. Alice then married her stage partner, Richard Yaryan, and changed her name to Alice Yaryan. In the late 1930s Alice sometimes used Alice Harper as a stage name (her father's first name was Harper) when she performed in the duo Harper and King. Also included in this series are: Alice's membership book in the American Guild of Variety Artists, in which dues stamps are pasted; a leather-bound diary kept in 1884 by Harper Fries while traveling in Mexico; posters and playbills, including one listing Alice as "Alice Landis, Dancing De Luxe"; programs from the Works Progress Administration Federal Theater in San Francisco and Los Angeles; contracts for the duo Yaryan and Landis, performing as the "Fast Stepping Man and Maid." The series includes many letters from Art Landis's brother, William H. Landis, to Alice; a letter from William to Alice in 1940 notes that Art Landis had moved to Mexico City, where he "might be able to cash in on his Spanish."
Note: Family photographs from Arthur and Alice's scrapbooks, many of Alice on assorted chorus lines and variety shows, can be found in the Arthur H. Landis Photograph Collection (ALBA Photo 66).
Series II: Correspondence, consists of incoming and outgoing correspondence, mostly from 1965 through 1985, mostly with SCW veterans (including Alva Bessie, Theodore [Ted] Cogswell, Carl Geiser, Steve Nelson, Albert Prago, Al Robbins, Saul Wellman, and Milton Wolff) dealing with matters pertaining to VALB, to Landis's books, to various writing and film projects, and to politics. What began as a letter from Landis seeking fellow veteran Cogswell's help in getting published (Cogswell was a science fiction writer and an officer of the Science Fiction Writers of America) blossomed into a long friendship in which the two read, critiqued, and collaborated on each other's work. Carl Geiser encloses in one letter a detailed memo prepared for the Prisoner Historical Committee of VALB, in which he reports his findings for writing a history of the Americans taken prisoner during the SCW. The file "General Correspondence" includes the enclosure in a letter to Landis of a Bill prepared for Congress seeking veterans' rights for the SCW volunteers.
Series III: Subject Files. This series documents a publishing venture with Manny Harriman, Camelot Publishing. It also includes contracts and correspondence with DAW Books, publishers of Landis's science fiction writings; an issue of Coven 13, published by Landis, and submissions of poetry, art, and stories to the magazine; book jackets for his published works; correspondence with Ring Lardner, Jr. requesting blurbs for Landis's books; and a typescript copy of "The Volunteers," a screenplay by Lardner about the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. Among the Spanish Civil War-era documents and ephemera are Landis's carnet militar (military passbook) for the International Brigades; a sign-up sheet collecting "pesetas for a fiesta," in Christmas of 1937; certificates of commendation in Spanish issued circa 1938 to Evelyn Hutchins Rahman, Wilhelm Werner, and Philip Detlo; the "Ocean Times," the on-board paper of the R.M.S. Ausonia, on which Landis returned from the War; and postcards of Lincoln Brigade members Yale Stuart and Sam Spiller, among others. VALB materials include meeting minutes, general mailings to members, and payment agreements for Landis's writings; marked-up drafts of the VALB Constitution; and an extended correspondence in the mid-1970s debating an unauthorized translation into Russian of an essay written by Landis for VALB.
Series IV: Writings. Landis's nonfiction focuses mainly on the U.S. volunteers' participation in the Spanish Civil War; his fiction and teleplays are largely fantasy and science fiction. Files relating to his writings on Abraham Lincoln Brigade include correspondence, research material, and notes sketching out the major battles in which Brigade members participated; notes and correspondence on the audiotaping of veterans; and typescripts. Files relating to Spain! The Unfinished Revolution include correspondence and reviews. The series also includes aryicles, book reviews, letters to the editor, and a screenplay, "The Volunteer (The Class of '37)", about the Lincoln Brigade. Fiction includes typescripts for novels Little Wars of the Omega Quadrant, A Path of Moonstones, and Roland.
Series V: Artifacts/Ephemera consists of two Spanish Civil War commemorative medals awarded to Landis in the 1960s; a pocket mileage converter; shoe taps and a banjo string, mementos kept by Alice Fries; and sheet music with vaudeville songs, including handwritten scores composed by Richard Yaryan.
Arrangement
Series I and 3 are arranged alphabetically; Series II is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, with Landis’ replies integrated. Series IV is arranged alphabetically by title of work, with related correspondence and research preceding typescript of each work. Series V is a flat box of artifacts and ephemera.
The files are organizeded in 5 series:
Missing Title
I. Family Files
II. Correspondence
III. Subject Files
IV. Writings
V. Artifacts/Memorabilia
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Arthur H. Landis Audiotape Collection (ALBA Audio 66)
Arthur H. Landis Photographs (ALBA Photo 66)
Other ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.
Separated Material
Photographs and audio tapes from the Arthur H. Landis Collection have been processed as separate collections.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- International brigades.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Campaigns.; Drafts (documents); Diaries; Correspondence.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |v Personal narratives, American.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Women.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Hospitals.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Printed ephemera.; Identity cards.; Artifacts (object genre); Research (document genres).; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American.; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. Archives; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Brigada Internacional, XV; Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. Historical Commission; Warren, Alvin; Harriman, Manny.; Hutchins, Evelyn, 1910-1982.; Rahman, Evelyn.; Cogswell, Theodore R. -- |v Pictorial works; Landis, Arthur H., 1917-1986; American Guild of Variety Artists; Geiser, Carl; Lardner, Ring, Jr., 1915-2000; Wolff, Milton.; Keaveny, James.; Wellman, Saul; Prago, Albert; Spain. Ejercito Popular de la Republica. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1904-1985 -- |v Pictorial works; Nelson, Steve, 1903-1993
- Series I: Family Files
  - Fries, Alice (Landis/Yaryan/Harper): Correspondence, undated, Feb 1963-Aug 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fries, Alice (Landis/Yaryan/Harper), 1903-1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fries, Harper: Diary, 1884 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Harper & King, undated, May 1930-Nov 1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Landis, William H. and Lola: Correspondence, undated, Jun 1929-Nov 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Landis, William H.: Drawings, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Landis, William H. and William D., undated, Jul 1916-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Landis, William N.: Correspondence, Jan 1916-[Aug 1918?] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Landis, William N., undated, 1916-1921 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yaryan & Landis, undated, Dec 1924-Oct 1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Bessie, Alvah, undated, Jan 1971-Oct 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cogswell, Theodore, undated, Jan 1975-Jun 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fishman, Moe, undated, Feb 1965-Jun 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Geiser, Carl, Dec 1978-Dec 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, undated, Dec 1965-Dec 1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Iceland, Ben, Mar 1984-Jan 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - International Publishers, Jul 1972-Jul 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - MacLeod, Donald, undated, Sep 1980-Feb 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Nelson, Steve, undated, Dec 1970-Feb 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Prago, Al, May 1976-Dec 1984 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Robbins, Al, undated, Nov 1974-Nov 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Science Fiction Writers of America, Jun 1974-Jul 1984 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Thayer, Donald, undated, Mar 1965-Feb 1973 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Tisa, John, Sep 1975-Dec 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Wellman, Saul, undated, Jul 1971-Nov 1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Wolff, Milton, undated, Jun 1970-May 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Series III: Subject Files
  - Book Covers, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Camelot Publishing, undated, Jun 1972-Jul 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Coven 13: Correspondence, undated, Jun 1969-Nov 1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Coven 13: Content, Copy, Art and Magazine, undated, Jan 1971-Feb 1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Coven 13: Submissions, undated, Jan 1969-Feb 1970 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - DAW Books: Correspondence, undated, Jan 1975-Nov 1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - DAW Books: General, undated, Jul 1976-Nov 1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Goldstein, Ben "Butch", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Hemingway, Ernest: "Eulogy to the American Dead in Spain", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Landis, Arthur: Curriculum Vitae, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Landis, Arthur: Ephemera, undated, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Landis, Arthur: Finances, 1968-1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Landis, Arthur: Identifications, Memberships, Diplomas, Certificate, 1932-1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Landis, Arthur: Medical, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Landis, Arthur: Memorial Tribute, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Lardner, Jr., Ring: Correspondence, May 1968-Aug 1979 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Lardner, Jr., Ring: Screenplay, Jun 1979 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - National Writers Union/Writers Guild, undated, Oct 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Publishers/Agents: Inquiries and Rejections, Feb 1969-Mar 1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Spanish Civil War, undated, Dec 1937-Jan 1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Spanish Civil War: Postcards, Currency, Graphics, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - TSR: The Game Wizards: Sample Game Script, Nov 1983-Jan 1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB): Correspondence, General, undated, Mar 1967-Apr 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - VALB: Correspondence re: "International Solidarity with the Spanish Republic", May 1965-Jun 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - VALB: General, undated, 1964, Feb 1971-Nov 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Writings, 1915-1985
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Correspondence, undated, Apr 1965-Dec 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Audiotapes, Notes, Correspondence, and Research, undated, Aug 1964-Apr 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Contract and Copyright Documents, undated, Mar 1966-May 1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Research Correspondence, undated, Mar 1963-Oct 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Research on Brunete, Quinto, and Belchite, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Research on Cardoba, Oct 1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Research on Ebro, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Research on the Fortress of Corchuna, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Research on Fuentes de Ebro, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: General Research, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Research on Jarama, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Research Data on Vets, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Research, Reviews, and Promotion, undated, Jul 1966-Feb 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Partial Draft of Typescript, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Typescript, pp. 4-120, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Typescript, pp. 121-244, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Typescript, Revised and Condensed Version, pp. 1-120, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Typescript, Revised and Condensed Version, pp. 121-244, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Typescript, Copyedited, Revised, and Condensed Version, pp. 1-140, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Typescript, Revised and Condensed Version, pp. 141-282, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Typescript, Revised and Condensed Version, pp. 283-396, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Typescript, Revised and Condensed Version, pp. 1-140, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Typescript, Revised and Condensed Version, pp. 141-282, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Typescript, Revised and Condensed Version, pp. 293-396, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "An Angels Song" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Blood for Maquis Guns" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "The Bull of Raphael Gaon" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Cheers: Paul Revere’s Companion" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - El Cid (book): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "Come Visit Me" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Count Down" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Donner Party (book): Synopsis, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "The Eye of Pachacamac" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "F.A.I. 1937" (short story): Typescript, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "F.A.I. 1937" (short story): Published Version, Oct 1957 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General Notes and Articles, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - General Notes and Articles, undated, 1968-1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - "Hard-Way Six" (teleplay): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - "Hemingway on Spain, 1931" (article) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - How I Left the White House and Was Born Again, or: The Adventures of Georgy Star Paws (book): Typescript, Introduction, and Notes, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - How I Left the White House and Was Born Again, or: The Adventures of Georgy Star Paws (book): Typescript, pp. 1-120, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - How I Left the White House and Was Born Again, or: The Adventures of Georgy Star Paws (book): Typescript, pp. 121-240, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - How I Left the White House and Was Born Again, or: The Adventures of Georgy Star Paws (book): Typescript, pp. 241-361, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - How I Left the White House and Was Born Again, or: The Adventures of Georgy Star Paws (book): Typescript, pp. 1-120, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - How I Left the White House and Was Born Again, or: The Adventures of Georgy Star Paws (book): Typescript, pp. 121-240, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - How I Left the White House and Was Born Again, or: The Adventures of Georgy Star Paws (book): Typescript, pp. 241-363, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "How the 15th International Abraham Lincoln Brigade Got Its Name" (article): Typescript, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "In Markham Town" (teleplay): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "In the Noonday Sun" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - "International Solidarity with the Spanish Republic" (article: Typescript [extract in Russian], 1969 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Letters to the Editor, undated, Jul 1974-Aug 1979 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Synopsis and Assorted Pages, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Typescript, revisions pp. 1-20, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Typescript, pp. 1-130, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Typescript, pp. 131-289, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Typescript, pp. 1-12 and pp. 100-167, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Typescript, pp. 1-90, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Final Draft of Typescript, pp. 1-120, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Final Draft of Typescript, pp. 121-240, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Final Draft of Typescript, pp. 241-350, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Typescript, pp. 1-115, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Typescript, pp. 116-230, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Little Wars of Omega Quadrant (book): Typescript, pp. 231-350, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Magick of Camelot (book): Typescript, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "My Mother’s a Princess" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - My Sister, My Love: Psycho Horror Drama (screenplay): Typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Of Cancer, An Aleph and the Year 2007" (article): Proposal Letters, Jun 1983 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Of Cancer, An Aleph and the Year 2007" (article): Typescript, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "The Passionate War: Some Observations" (book review): Typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - A Path of Moonstones" (book): Notes, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - A Path of Moonstones" (book): Partial Typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - A Path of Moonstones" (book): Typescript, pp. 1-120, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - A Path of Moonstones" (book): Typescript, pp. 121-241, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - A Path of Moonstones" (book): Typescript, pp. 242-360, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - A Path of Moonstones" (book): Typescript, pp. 1-120, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - A Path of Moonstones" (book): Typescript, pp. 121-241, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - A Path of Moonstones" (book): Typescript, pp. 242-360, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "Perspective" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - "Ragnarok, the Twilight of the Gods" (short story): Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - "Representation" (short story): Typescript, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Roland (book): Synopsis, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Roland (book): Typescript, pp. 1-163, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Roland (book): Typescript, pp. 164-311, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Roland (book): Typescript, pp. 312-439, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Spain and Munich: Windows to Vietnam" (article): Typescripts, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Spain! An Unfinished Revolution: Contract and Copyright, 1972, Jul 1975-Jan 1985 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Spain! An Unfinished Revolution: Correspondence, undated, Jan 1972-Nov 1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Spain! An Unfinished Revolution: Reviews and Promotion, undated, Sep 1972-Sep 1975 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - The Square and the Circle (screenplay): Synopsis, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)